<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Xingjian Pan's Blog - 书影音</title><link href="http://xingjian.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://xingjian.me/feeds/shu-ying-yin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://xingjian.me/</id><updated>2013-07-20T21:22:30+08:00</updated><entry><title>Note on the power of habits</title><link href="http://xingjian.me/notes-on-the-power-of-habits.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-20T21:22:30+08:00</published><updated>2013-07-20T21:22:30+08:00</updated><author><name>Xingjian Pan</name></author><id>tag:xingjian.me,2013-07-20:/notes-on-the-power-of-habits.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What this book about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How habit works?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to develop a new habit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get out of a bad habit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The first shock from this book.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People now get used to the habits of using toothpaste to brush their teeth, but this habit doesn't exist for majority people in …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What this book about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How habit works?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to develop a new habit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get out of a bad habit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The first shock from this book.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People now get used to the habits of using toothpaste to brush their teeth, but this habit doesn't exist for majority people in the world 50 years ago. A clever advertiser actually build this habit for the rest of the people to help selling the toothpaste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's said using toothpaste is not really useful at all. But people like the cool feeling when using toothpaste and this reminds them they have done a routine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not just toothpaste, many things that are now &lt;em&gt;considered a necesssary&lt;/em&gt; in original people's shopping cart, are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; common 50 or 100 years go.  Economics development is an imporant factor. But we should ask ourselves, how we come to the habit of using them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People developed the habits of using something and then feel it's a necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the book is useful for me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it actually make it clear, habit, like many things else, can be &lt;em&gt;developed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual can use the same techinque to develop &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; habits that can make their life better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the habit is there, it actually works by itself. People who has the habit to get up earlier don't consider it a pain to get up earlier anymore, as it become their habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the book is useful for corporates?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like individuals, companies also have their habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By developing a powerful and healthy habit, a company can realize substantial competitive advantage over oters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book give out a great example. CEO Paul O'Neill set the habit of alwasy string for 0 injuries for the company, which turns out to change a lot of things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to develop a habit?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a Cue - a trigger for doing something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routine - what actually get done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reward - positive feedback if done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Craving for reward - the hidded force. This is the driving force behind every good or bad habit. it's important find find the craving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not all habits are created equal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a few habits, also knowns as &lt;em&gt;keynote habit&lt;/em&gt; play a much important role than other habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By focusing on developing one or two &lt;em&gt;keynote habit&lt;/em&gt;, it's said other habits, usually good ones, will naturally come.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An example of such &lt;em&gt;keynote habits&lt;/em&gt; is daily exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="读书笔记"></category></entry></feed>